window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "Computer_Network - Data_Link_Layer — Slot 5 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Data_Link_Layer — Slot 5",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>The minimum frame size required for a CSMA/CD based computer network running at 1Gbps on a 200m cable with a link speed of \\(2\\times 10^{8} m / sec\\) is: <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2008)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>125bytes</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>250bytes</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>500bytes</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>250bytes</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3376/gate2008-it-65\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>A 1 Mbps satellite link connects two ground stations. The altitude of the satellite is 36,504 km and speed of the signal is \\(3 \\times 10^8\\)m/s. What should be the packet size for a channel utilization of 25% for a satellite link using go-back-127 sliding window protocol?<br> Assume that the acknowledgment packets are negligible in size and that there are no errors during communication. <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2008)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>120 bytes</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>60 bytes</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>240 bytes</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>90 bytes</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>120 bytes</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3375/gate2008-it-64\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>A computer on a 10Mbps network is regulated by a token bucket. The token\nbucket is filled at a rate of 2Mbps. It is initially filled to capacity with 16Megabits.\nWhat is the maximum duration for which the computer can transmit at the full 10Mbps? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2008)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>1.6 seconds</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>2 seconds</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>5 seconds</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>8 seconds</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>2 seconds</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/481/gate2008-58#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>An Ethernet hub <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>functions as a repeater</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>connects to a digital PBX</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>connects to a token-ring network</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>functions as a gateway</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>functions as a repeater</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/49494/isro2007-21\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>Consider a token ring topology with N stations (numbered 1 to N) running token ring protocol where the stations are equally spaced. When a station gets the token it is allowed to send one frame of fixed size. Ring latency is \\(t_{p}\\), while the transmission time of a frame is \\(t_{t}\\). All other latencies can be neglected. <br>The maximum utilization of the token ring when \\(t_{t}\\) = 5 ms, \\(t_{p}\\) = 3 ms, N = 15 is: <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>0.545</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>0.655</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>0.9375</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>0.961</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>0.961</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3527/gate2007-it-75\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>Consider a token ring topology with N stations (numbered 1 to N) running token ring protocol where the stations are equally spaced. When a station gets the token it is allowed to send one frame of fixed size. Ring latency is \\(t_{p}\\), while the transmission time of a frame is \\(t_{t}\\). All other latencies can be neglected. <br>The maximum utilization of the token ring when \\(t_{t}\\) = 3 ms, \\(t_{p}\\) = 5 ms, N = 10 is: <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>0.545</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>0.6</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>0.857</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>0.961</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>0.857</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3526/gate2007-it-74\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>A broadcast channel has 10 nodes and total capacity of 10 Mbps. It uses polling for medium access. Once a node finishes transmission, there is a polling delay of 80 \\(\\mu s\\) to poll the next node. Whenever a node is polled, it is allowed to transmit a maximum of 1000 bytes. The maximum throughput of the broadcast channel is: <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>1 Mbps</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>100/11 Mbps</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>10 Mbps</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>100 Mbps</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>100/11 Mbps</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3509/gate2007-it-64\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>An error correcting code has the following code words: 00000000, 00001111, 01010101, 10101010, 11110000. What is the maximum number of bit errors that can be corrected? <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>0</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>3</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>1</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>2</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>1</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3478/gate2007-it-43\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>The distance between two stations M and N is L kilometers. All frames are K bits long. The propagation delay per kilometer is t seconds. Let R bits/second be the channel capacity. Assuming that processing delay is negligible, the minimum number of bits for the sequence number field in a frame for maximum utilization, when the sliding window protocol is used, is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\([log_{2}\\frac{2LtR+2K}{K}]\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\([log_{2}\\frac{2LtR}{K}]\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\([log_{2}\\frac{2LtR+K}{K}]\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\([log_{2}\\frac{2LtR+2K}{2K}]\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>\\([log_{2}\\frac{2LtR+K}{K}]\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1267/gate2007-69#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>The message 11001001 is to be transmitted using the CRC polynomial \\(x^{3}\\)+1 to\nprotect it from errors. The message that should be transmitted is: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>11001001000</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>11001001011</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>11001010</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>110010010011</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>11001001011</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1266/gate2007-68#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>In a token ring network the transmission speed is \\(10^{7}\\) bps and the propagation\nspeed is 200 metres/\\(\\mu s\\). The 1-bit delay in this network is equivalent to: <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>500 metres of cable.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>200 metres of cable.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>50 metres of cable.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>20 metres of cable.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>20 metres of cable.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1264/gate2007-66#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>There are n stations in a slotted LAN. Each station attempts to transmit with a probability p in each time slot. What is the probability that ONLY one station transmits in a given time slot? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2007)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(np(1-p)^{n-1}\\)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>\\((1-p)^{n-1}\\)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>\\(p(1-p)^{n-1}\\)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>\\(1-(1-p)^{n-1}\\)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>\\(np(1-p)^{n-1}\\)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1263/gate2007-65#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>On a wireless link, the probability of packet error is 0.2. A stop-and-wait protocol is used to transfer data across the link. The channel condition is assumed to be independent of transmission to transmission. What is the average number of transmission attempts required to transfer 100 packets? <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2006)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>100</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>125</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>150</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>200</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>125</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3612/gate2006-it-68\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>A link of capacity 100 Mbps is carrying traffic from a number of sources. Each source generates an on-off traffic stream; when the source is on, the rate of traffic is 10 Mbps, and when the source is off, the rate of traffic is zero. The duty cycle, which is the ratio of on-time to off-time, is 1:2. When there is no buffer at the link, the minimum number of sources that can be multiplexed on the link so that link capacity is not wasted and no data loss occurs is S1. Assuming that all sources are synchronized and that the link is provided with a large buffer, the maximum number of sources that can be multiplexed so that no data loss occurs is S2. The values of S1 and S2 are, respectively, <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2006)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>10 and 30</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>12 and 25</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>5 and 33</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>15 and 22</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>10 and 30</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3611/gate2006-it-67\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>A router has two full-duplex Ethernet interfaces each operating at 100 Mb/s. Ethernet frames are at least 84 bytes long (including the Preamble and the Inter-Packet-Gap). The maximum packet processing time at the router for wirespeed forwarding to be possible is (in micro-seconds) <br><br><strong>(GATE IT 2006)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>0.01</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>3.36</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>6.72</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>8</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>3.36</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/3610/gate2006-it-66\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
